If you want to turn off the subtitles,
click [setting]-[tooltips]-['on' for PC, 'close' for mobile].
Hello.
Today, we are going to learn about the face.
The character's face.
But some may start drawing the facial part
before they work on the body.
Most people start drawing
because they want to draw a beautiful character.
The reason I put the facial part after the body is simply that it's important.
It's really important.
Even some people say that
you can get a job
if you can just draw the face successfully.
But you should be able to draw the other parts as well.
Especially the body.
But that shows how important the face is.
Some people can draw the body well
while they express the facial part in poorly.
This is true in realistic drawing.
And of course, in casual drawing as well.
So the face is really important.
Therefore,
since
this part is important,
it's difficult at the same time.
In our brain,
there's a separate part where you can recognize a person's expressions.
That means the human brain
can catch the expressions
in detail.
Because of that,
you may know if you have some experience in facial drawing.
If I get just one pixel wrong,
it becomes weird.
So you can catch tiny glitches at one glance.
Also, the face
has a lot of details
like bumpy bones,
and several muscles.
More than any other part of the human body.
So the more you dig into the details,
the more you have to study.
So let's have a look into these parts as well.
When you work on this part,
there are
two important things
you have to set first.
So you need sophisticated expressions
when you work on the face.
Then you can say your drawing is stabilized.
And secondly,
you have to make it look good.
Since this is commercial art, it's a necessary skill.
But when the character isn't good-looking,
and you want to do some artistic works,
then
it may not be essential.
But if you are into the casual style
which is more commercial art,
it will be essential.
Of course, this could be your standard of beauty,
but it could be a popular aesthetic standard.
We will go through both of these today.
How to draw the face accurately.
And several tips to make it look good.
But before we move on,
I'll tell you something that's even more important
to do with accuracy.
The first thing we're going to see is a head shape.
In the previous lecture,
we talked about the ratio,
and the ratio of the human face is 2:1.
In the case of a casual character,
it's a bit different.
So it'll be up to 1.8.
If we have a face with that proportion,
it will only look like that when we look at it up front.
Today, I'll turn this around.
But before we go on,
I want to tell you something
about the cuboid shape.
By now, you would have noticed that
when drawing the human body,
you would draw cuboids a lot.
Especially, when you're drawing the head,
you would draw this shape a lot.
It's as if a smaller cuboid was cut off from a larger cuboid.
So, you need to be good at drawing cuboids.
The important thing with cuboids
is that
you need to be able to apply perspective.
Note that the upper side and the underside
don't have the same perspective applied.
If a high-angle is applied here, it would be applied more here.
Remember that.
So, let's say we're looking at it from here.
If this is the eye level,
if it goes up, a low-angle would be applied a bit.
And as it goes upwards, it would be applied more.
It would just look flat from here.
Go downwards, and a high-angle would be applied a bit.
Go downwards a bit more, and it would be applied more.
So, you should be able to
apply different amounts of perspective to a character's face.
You need to be able to draw how the dimensions would change.
That's why you should practice
drawing cuboids as much as you can.
I'll recommend that you do this
when you're drawing the head.
Now, let's go back.
Overall, the head looks like
a cuboid.
A head is basically a cuboid
with a chin attached to it.
Think of it like that.
If we look at it from the side,
the overall shape would look like this.
Like what I drew,
the chin sticks
to the counterpoint.
But, the proportion changes a bit
with casual-style characters.
In the case of casual style,
the head becomes bigger compared to a realistic drawing style.
So, in this process,
draw as if the forehead and the back of the head
are pulled backward.
It looks like an alien for now.
The back of their head is really big.
Just like an alien.
It's good to make a shape
where the back of their head is
a bit big and the top is high.
As a result,
the shape that comes out like this
is divided into half of the lower part
and half of this part,
you can think of it as a split.
Some people draw it like this
when they put on facial expressions.
Some people draw it like this,
to set the basic shape of the face.
I don't recommend it.
Some people say
when you draw a picture for the first time,
draw a cross line first.
The people who are learning take it
as it is and start by drawing a cross line.
Not many people use it properly
after drawing a cross line.
Even after they drew this,
they draw the eyes at a completely different spot.
Or, when they draw the nose, they might not draw on this line.
In fact, it is impossible to draw a cross line
on the face.
Why is that?
The curves on our faces aren't that simple.
No one has a flat face like that.
When we look at our head, the forehead goes slightly upwards
if we're looking at it sideways.
The eyebrow bones bulge out a bit.
And the eye sockets go in.
The nose bridge goes in
and then the nose pops out.
The underside of the nose goes in, pops out, then goes in.
Then, the philtrum and the lips pop out.
The chin goes in, but the bottom of it pops out.
You can see that it is very detailed.
That's why when you finish it off as one line,
you'll get a lot of details wrong.
So, I don't recommend drawing a cross line.
So, how would you draw guidelines?
Remember how we divided the head into cuboids?
Draw the guidelines on them.
Draw the center lines on the cuboid
that's on the top.
Then, you might wonder if it's okay
because this one's more simplified than
the one we drew previously.
The line we're drawing is a guideline, no matter what.
You're drawing this line to check if
what you're drawing is in the center.
First, we'd draw straight lines.
Although we can't get detailed information from it,
it won't be the wrong information.
So, first, draw a line
that goes through the center.
That's the first step.
The second one will come out later.
Let's take a look at the proportions
of the face.
So basically this line in the middle is
eye-level.
This is where you are going to draw the eyes.
The size of the eyes will be different for each person.
I'm going to draw them bigger today.
So that it is discernible.
The eyes are here at this level.
If the eyes go in like this,
there are ear grooves at the same height as this.
We usually wear glasses.
So the character has to be able to wear glasses.
Anyway, if you wear glasses,
the height of these glasses has to match the eye level.
It is easy to see that the height of the ear is
the same as the height of the eye.
Let's say the ears are here.
Then it'll be very uncomfortable when you wear glasses.
They slid down.
Or if it goes up, it'll be uncomfortable as well.
Therefore, it is important to draw this groove the same
as the height of the eye.
This becomes the center of the side of the head.
In the center of the side head,
of course, to be exact, it's slightly in the front rather than the center.
Because we extended the back of the head at the early stage.
So we don't need to include it.
It's slightly towards the front rather than the center.
But let's memorize it as the center of the side of the head.
I'm going to draw the other eye.
Let's talk about the details of the eyes later.
So let's go for the proportion part first.
Now, we need to know where the nose and mouth are.
We drew this square
and put the chin on the bottom.
Supposed it's the chin,
you can think of the height of the mouth as the center.
So, I'll draw the nose here.
The mouth should go around here.
It will be a bit above the center.
We can say that the teeth
go in
like this, in this area.
So, that's how we would set the proportions for the face.
And if you can do that,
you'll have a bald person like this.
So, let's review how the neck would stick to the head.
Draw the sternocleidomastoid muscle, then stick the neck to the back of the head.
Its thickness will be the same length as the area between the canthi if it's a male character.
Although it is not exact,
I think this could be the final shape.
This is the approximate proportion of the face.
Let's go into more detail now.
The first thing to go into detail about is the eyes.
When we draw the casual face of a character,
the most important part
which requires a lot of effort at the same time
would be the eyes.
If you are going to draw the eyes, you need to know the structure of the eyes.
You need to be able to know the detailed structure
near the area where the eyes go in.
It may sound difficult.
But let's try it.
When we look at our eyes in profile,
there's the eye socket,
where our eyeballs would go in.
From there, our eyes would bulge out.
And, our eyelids cover that
like this.
These would form the overall eye.
So, that's the basic shape of the eye.
So, what would be important from here?
First of all, the eye itself is a hole.
It goes inwards.
Why is this important?
It becomes important
when the character's head looks in a certain direction.
I didn't apply that here.
But, let's see what happens
if we actually did apply that.
This is how it would look.
You might ask what's different.
We call this bone here
the eyelid bone.
The eyebrows would be drawn on top of here.
In fact, if you touch your eyebrows,
you can check that it's solid underneath.
This is because the bones around the eyes bulge out.
See how the character's looking to the left?
So, this eyebrow bone
would bulge out to the left
compared to the eye, which goes inwards.
So, what would happen if the character was looking to the right?
If it does so,
the eyebrow bone would bulge out to the right.
And the eye would bulge out from the inside.
And under here,
there would be the cheekbone.
Make sure the cheekbones pop out a bit.
Then, you'll have the overall shape of the eyes.
So if you look into the whole shape of the face,
you can see that this is what it looks like this.
Like this,
depending on the knowledge of the structure,
the accuracy of the face varies.
So please remember it.
I emphasize this part every time,
but people often make mistakes.
This part is really difficult.
Therefore,
if you don't get this part,
then lookup for some photos, and copy drawing.
Especially the face of the elderly,
or middle-aged men.
Or marble statues, etc.
So try to practice
and analyze this part.
People often make mistakes in this part.
That's why I keep emphasizing it.
Then,
now you know the overall structure of the eyes, you should know about the eyes.
The eyes.
Everyone applies deformers differently.
So, I'll tell you which parts
you could focus on
when you're creating your own style.
So let's look into the basic structure of the eyes.
So here's the upper eyelid.
Let's go into detail.
Let's divide the upper eyelid
into three lines.
There's the eye wall
right under this inner eyebrow.
It's basically skin.
If this is the eyebrow,
there's the eye wall underneath it.
I'm going over this area because
some of you
may draw the eye like this.
Like this,
some people express the inside in two lines
and this one would be the eyeball.
Depending on the person, some people draw it like this.
Usually, depending on the characters,
they have four lines.
And the fifth line,
right next to the eye.
Underneath the eye,
you may draw it in different ways.
I'll draw two this time.
So there are about seven lines
in the overall appearance of the eye.
If you draw additional things here,
you could draw this.
This is the red triangular area in front of the eyes.
There are people who draw this area.
I'll set this to number 8 just in case.
Now, double eyelids could be formed here.
So, what is it?
When there's too much skin above the eye,
it will be folded because there isn't enough space.
After it's folded, our eyes would pop out.
This would be the double eyelid.
Some people have thick double eyelids, while others have thin double eyelids.
Some people only have it on one eye.
I usually draw double eyelids for my characters.
I will go through this part later
but around the eyes,
people often draw double eyelids a lot
to make it look good.
Then these double eyelids will be the ninth line.
So the eyebrows come out from here.
Some people draw another line like this before the eyebrows.
Sometimes people draw a line like this.
So you may wonder if this is the triple eyelid.
To be exact, think of it as the seat under the eyes
rather than the double eyelids.
That means,
if the character opens their eyes
it would reach up to this line
so this line would be the limit line.
These lines are guidelines
to let you know the boundaries
such as the eyeball
and the bone.
Some people applied this without knowing the reason
what those are for.
Many people who practiced drawing
while copying casual style characters
draw a line right here.
But, they can't answer why they drew this line.
So,
let's find out what this line is for.
Although these days, a lot of people don't draw this line.
It's a line that is used a lot in the old casual drawing style.
So here's the tenth line.
Let's say this is the upper part of the eye, then we should look at the lower part.
In the lower part of the eyes,
on the outer right here,
some people draw another line like this.
So you may wonder what it is.
This line would be the part
where when you're looking at the eye from the side,
this skin area
that is right below the eye.
That skin part stays the same
and the eyelashes stick to this part.
If they stick more inwards,
your eyes would hurt.
The eyebrows are attached to the outside of this area.
So, this line describes
the part where the eyebrows would be attached.
So, there are people that draw like this.
Most people who draw like this
are describing this area.
The area where the skin is folded.
And, furthermore,
there are people who draw additional curves underneath.
However,
this won't be too necessary.
So, these are the curves we can see around the eye area.
So, what next?
Now, you should find your drawing style.
Let me give you an example.
For example, if you want to draw a character with a sharp impression,
you can omit numbers 2 and 3.
But how?
One, two, and three.
And then direct to five.
And skip seven, six,
eight as well.
Like this,
draw double eyelids.
If you don't want to draw the double eyelids,
draw a space here,
and attach the eyebrows.
Make sure they go outwards like this.
This is how you would apply deformers.
If you express everything,
the character would look very gentle.
So expressing all of these,
you can give it a mature look.
One, two, three.
By giving it subtle changes in angle,
when you omit these, the character would be extremely stylized.
This eye would be used often for 'chibi' characters.
On the other hand, the eye at the bottom
has a more realistic style.
So you can adjust the degree of deformers
depending on
whether you use more or less line information.
And depending on how you change the line,
the shape of the eyeball and the character's impression will change.
So it's good to learn some patterns.
Let's check out the patterns that people often use.
The first case is the one with a sharp impression.
It's a case where it looks half-open.
In this case, the double eyelid spreads out slightly.
Why does it spread out?
Remember when I said
this area is formed when the eyes are open, and there is little space.
But, if we only open our eyes halfway, there's space left,
so the double eyelids are formed naturally.
So, now we have a half-open eye.
We use this design for hollow characters.
Now, I'll make the eyes a bit slanted.
These eyes are often used for female characters that look like a cat.
I'll raise it.
It goes a bit outwards, then goes downwards.
So it would look like this.
Again, this eye is often used for female characters that look like a cat.
Now, we can slant the eyes upwards
or downwards.
If they go downwards,
the character will look more gentle.
Like this.
Usually in this case,
depending on the designer,
some people draw their eyes like this.
Of course, the eyes may look weird in some cases.
They might look old-fashioned.
So you do it on a case-by-case basis.
Like this,
and
in this case it looks more gentle
if you lower the ends of the eyes.
In this case, even the bottom line can be omitted.
You've seen this before, right?
So, the character would look very gentle.
If you look at another example,
this would be usually applied to male characters.
Here, you would modify the lower area.
So far, we modified only the upper area.
So, now, let's modify the lower area.
This could also be related to expressions.
When you push the lower curve upwards,
the character tends to have a sharper impression.
It would be much sharper
than the eye I drew above.
And it looks more masculine.
And, if we raise this lower part upwards,
it will look as if the character's frowning.
Like this.
Other than these, we can create many different eyes.
Some people draw square shaped eyes.
There are also people
who draw eyes as round as possible, without drawing all these lines.
There are many scenarios.
But, although there are many scenarios,
your character would look different depending on
how you express these lines.
So, you should expand what you can express.
Practice drawing different eye shapes
and use them
according to your needs.
So, you can draw a character's eyes
like this.
What was the important point?
The first one was the eye socket.
This three-dimensional shape is really important, so please remember it well.
The second was the structure of the eyes and the patterns.
And the third one,
would be the pupil.
They said the pupils look like this.
There's something important here.
There's a part that we usually express as pupils.
This spot in the middle
is where your pupils go.
It's a spot like this.
So, the shape goes inwards.
Why is this important?
When the character
looks to the left,
the eye will look like this.
So, many people
just draw the pupil at the center.
But, it won't look three-dimensional this way.
To draw accurately,
let's make the pupils a bit thick,
around this much.
So, now we would draw the pupil,
like this.
If you do this,
you can draw a more three-dimensional face.
Of course, we apply deformers to this area.
What is it?
We would slightly modify the drawing.
For example, if you want to draw a character that looks to the left.
In that case,
although it does look like
it's looking to the left,
it's not too clear.
So to fix that issue,
to make it more clear,
you may express it like this.
So it looks more clear.
You can do that, but basically, it goes inwards.
Keep in mind that the pupil is located like that.
I'll tell you one more thing.
The gaze.
When we draw the character's gaze,
many people make mistakes here.
Some of you may have felt like
your character's eyes are cross-eyed.
This especially happens when you are drawing the character's face from the front.
If you draw the face, the character's eyes could be cross-eyed.
Why does that happen?
Because we actually draw cross-eyes.
If you look at people's gaze,
when people perceive an object,
it means their eyes come into focus.
When you were young, you might have seen friends
who put out a finger and stare at it
to become cross-eyed.
So, your gaze will meet somewhere at a certain point.
That would mean our eyes
are always a bit cross-eyed.
If they're looking at the same place, that itself is an error.
Therefore,
in a half-sided state...
In this state,
let's say it's looking to the right.
Let's say you look to the right, about this point.
This eye on the right moves a bit.
On the other hand, the left eye
has to match the spot right here.
It has to stick to the wall and go in like this.
So this eye has an outer wall on the right side
This means that the outer wall should not be left on the right side.
"You have to look at both eyes in the same way."
The people who drew it like this
may have experienced that it's hard to see the direction of the face.
It kind of becomes cross-eyed.
I'm sure you've experienced it before.
So to prevent that,
I'm going to overlap this gaze in one place,
so the fact that they allow them to meet in one place
becomes clear.
That was the eyeball part.
The next thing you need to look at is both the nose and the mouth.
The nose is also the most omitted part of the casual style.
I often
said the eye part is the part that we apply the deformers to the most.
That's what I said...
This is almost the same as the eye part.
Or, depending on how you interpret it,
The part where deformers go in more than the eyes is the nose.
What it means is that we don't draw it without appropriate details.
The nose is normally very complicated.
If you look at the actual nose,
It looks like this.
To be honest,
if I just draw it as it is,
it'd look very ugly.
Depending on the person who expresses the nose,
Some people said it looks like an alien.
Then how could you make the nose look casual?
I'll talk about the age group.
Here it's a question of impressions.
I'm going to draw two characters.
Let's guess which one looks younger.
In the first case,
I will raise the eyebrows
as much as I can.
And I'm going to put the nose as close as possible to the eyes.
I'm going to put the lips there as much as I can.
Now, the second case.
In the second case,
I'm going to add some eyebrows.
And lower the nose and mouth as much as possible.
Between the two, which one looks more mature?
When you put it down like this,
no matter how many times I look at it,
among these characters
If you look at them, the one on the right looks like a dad.
And this one is the baby.
It's going to be like that.
What I'm saying is
the distance between the eyes and eyebrows is far.
The closer the nose and mouth are to the eyes,
the cuter the impression.
And as the face gets smaller,
and the head gets bigger, the cuter it becomes.
In other words,
the smaller the head and the bigger the face,
the closer the eyes and eyebrows are,
and the farther the eyes, nose, and mouth are,
that makes the character look more mature.
So, at this time,
with the expression of the nose,
sometimes there might be some slight differences.
Let me give you an example.
When I have this face,
and
if you want to make it look younger,
and express it in the nose, it'll look like this.
In this line,
which one do you think is more effective, the upper or the lower?
The answer is the upper side.
I'm going to draw the upper part of the nose.
So to help the eyes to get closer,
I used the baby's case,
the one on the top left.
If you make it this close,
it gives the impression that the character looks younger.
On the other side,
I'll take this character's face shape.
And I'm going to bring it here and make up the lower part.
Create the lower part,
and if you lower the nose a bit,
even though we were at the same face,
you'll be able to see that it looks more mature.
If you draw the mouth like this,
even when you didn't change the proportion
and the face shape,
you'll be able to see the change in the character's impression.
Like this, the deformers on the nose,
depending on what kind of impression you want to give,
the part you give the impression to would change.
When it comes to if you should divide it into cases,
some people draw it like a triangle,
and I said the nose looks like this before.
This is the first case.
Some people draw it like this.
Or others use shapes to draw the side of the nose.
So the second case is to express the top of the nose.
The third case,
is that only the lower side of the nose is expressed.
The fourth case,
is a case where you draw the sides and nostrils together.
This is used a lot when you draw half side.
You've probably seen this line before.
Something like this.
The fifth case
is the one with both nostrils.
Some people draw it like this.
The difference from this one is
one side of this here stands up a bit more.
This is the center of the nose.
Usually, the cases are divided like this.
You can control the character's age by choosing one.
Now, the mouth.
You don't have to make the mouth big.
Deformers are applied a lot
in this part.
Depending on how you use them,
no matter what part of the face it is,
deformers can be applied a lot.
You may have seen this in casual characters,
like this one.
This character's mouth is attached to the side.
Since the center of the face is here,
this makes the mouth really crooked.
There's a hole next to the mouth.
So if you watch it in 3D, it'll look really ugly.
But this works in 2D illustrations.
So you can use it.
You can apply deformers a lot in this section.
Then what do you need to know from the mouth section?
Let's move on after getting the basics.
For female characters, it's based on the inner part of the eye.
The size of the mouth would be
as much as you can fit on the inner side.
If it's bigger than this, the mouth looks too big.
For the male character,
the standard for adult males is the center of both eyes.
Literally at the center.
But it's better to push it in a little bit.
So it would suit the character more.
So that's about it.
By keeping the size,
You can adjust the deformers.
When you adjust the deformers for the mouth,
let's look at the cases for this, too.
A case that only expresses the upper teeth.
And one that expresses the lower lip only,
these are the cases that come up often.
And if you loosen up the deformers,
there's a case for expressing the three-dimensional effect of the teeth.
And there's the case where you draw the lower teeth as well.
If I loosen it up a bit more,
it goes into the shape of the teeth.
Or you can just depict the fangs on this side,
like this.
But the nose and eyes don't come out very well.
But the deformers that come up often in the mouth,
I'm sure you've seen this a lot.
A sharp tooth.
There are cases where there is a lot of deformation in the teeth,
or even if it's a pointy tooth, I'll loosen up the deformers.
Some people try to make it realistic.
Or there's a mouth that has a lot of deformers in it.
The teeth look good in this mouth.
There will be different patterns
but it could be like this.
The important thing is a standard for a mouth Deformer.
If you followed the standard, then the Deformer would be very free.
If there's a character you want to draw who is aged,
then you would draw its mouth with fewer deformers applied.
And if you want to draw a younger character,
and if you use a mouth with a lot of deformers applied,
you'll be able to fit in.
That was a brief introduction to the eyes, nose, and lips.
Ears are just legitimate ears.
You can practice while looking at the pictures.
It's called the inner ear flap.
I'm going to express the ear flap to a certain extent.
Some people have protruding parts under their ears,
but people don't use this part for a casual character.
I think you can recognize that it's enough to draw.
Let me tell you something important.
It's a three-dimensional part that the ears stick to.
When you look at the face from the top,
the part with the ears is diagonally attached.
It's not attached like this.
There are people who get confused with this.
Let's be careful not to make a mistake.
So, now, we finished the overall shape of the head,
and the cuboid shape of the head,
and the overall features of the face.
While assembling this,
you need to be able to see the details of the face shape.
We didn't go through much of the face shape yet.
Let's take a look at it.
Like we did before,
I'm going to make the basic shape of the head.
Draw the center line here.
It'd be nice if you widen the top here.
Make the back a little wider as well.
If you get to draw a casual character's
basic head shape,
now you will be able to apply
the facial features easily.
But there might be one thing that makes you get stuck here.
It's the perspective.
It's so hard to apply perspective to the face.
I meet a lot of people with this issue.
So when that happens,
how could you overcome this?
I'll tell you briefly.
The basic shape of the eyes...
let's use the eyes.
I'm going to draw this eye at a low angle.
How should you draw it?
If you draw it like this,
it's done.
You might think, "What is this?"
That's what's important.
The line which was straight here,
bends down here.
Just to let you know, the base of this line is
the line I drew on the face.
We drew the center line once before.
This line itself is the center of the eyes.
If this part bends like this,
then apply it to the other part of the eye as well.
Please bend it at the same angle.
One, two
and then
to fit the angle,
just understand it as
giving different 'levels' to the curvature.
What I'm saying is,
for example, I basically drew this line
so when there's no perspective applied inside,
and when it's level zero,
the lower the angle,
then it becomes level 1.
The higher the angle is,
let's say it's becomes level one.
So, I added a low angle.
Then, this line will be loosened like this.
Then let's say it's in a very low angle.
Then, this line will be flipped at that point.
On the other hand, suppose you saw this line as a high angle.
Then, you'll have to dig a little lower.
Then, if you thought it was a higher angle,
then you'll get a lot of holes down there.
It changes like this.
So, you would modify these lines a bit
depending on how much
the low angle is applied.
So, think of dividing them into different levels.
If you look at the numbers here,
let's approach it like math.
The eyes are at a low angle of level 2.
And this eye is basically straight.
So, it's close to Level 0. And 0+2 is 2.
So, this one is on Level 2, and there is a low angle applied.
This line goes down a little bit.
So, this eye's angle is at Minus level 1.
Then, here, I'll apply level 2
to this angle, too.
Then what's Minus level 1 plus level 2?
It's level 1.
Then, let's use the line that's a bit loose.
Instead of that, you would draw it as
a line that's headed to the center a bit.
So, it would be level 1.
If you think about it that way,
when you apply the angle,
it'll be easier to apply.
Now then,
if the eyes with the low angle
look like this,
then we need to draw eyes with a high angle as well.
It's the opposite, so it's about the same.
It's not that different.
You can draw it like this.
Even when you can just draw the basic type,
and if you
want to give this kind of impression,
remember the gentle eye that we drew previously?
How would this eye be different from that?
I said this side is just a straight line, so it's level 0.
But this is already dug up.
Let's say it has a level 1 line.
I applied this low angle here.
Then it'll be level 3.
When you look at the same angle,
it goes up a bit higher.
On the other hand, since it's expressed in a straight line,
similar to this line,
like this,
this is how the low angle is applied.
You can apply various facial expressions.
So when you put in the high angle...
On the other hand, compared to this eye,
we need to dig a bit more.
We should put it in.
By using this,
you can practice a lot.
Now we get to apply the facial features like this.
The next one is what we've done earlier.
Let's take a look at the face shape.
I told you about the face shape.
Let's just look into it briefly.
First of all,
the eyelids.
As I said before, in the overall structure of the eyes
like this, the eyebrows stick out.
And the eyes look like they're in the center.
Therefore, this part of the face is also exposed on the outer line.
I'm slightly looking towards the top of the forehead.
It's not completely vertical,
but it's like looking up.
It's important to draw it flat.
When we hit our friend's forehead,
it makes a clapping sound.
Why would there be a clapping sound?
If your forehead is round, you can't make a clapping sound.
We can hear the sound.
The reason why there's a clapping sound when you hit your forehead
is because it looks flat.
I'm going to express the cheekbones.
Some people say cheekbones stick out like this.
People don't emphasize the cheekbones in casual characters.
So, people often don't express
cheekbones a lot.
You can think of it as lowering it vertically.
Lowering it down like that,
we have a chin.
The chin is slightly lower than the ears.
From this point,
on the chin below,
it usually starts a little above the center.
Some people put it down to the center,
from about 1/3 of the point,
it goes down steeply like this.
The chin is basically straight.
When you draw the chin,
don't think of it as a curve.
When you draw a character's face, you have to draw it in a circle.
You can't cut the bones.
Why does this side look so round?
When you look at it from the front,
the reason why the chin looks round
and the reason why the cheeks are sticking out
is because you are seeing them from a high angle.
So we are looking from this area.
This one is a bit lower.
And it's like a high angle.
Therefore, this side looks a bit more round.
The bone line itself doesn't bend and go in.
So, draw a straight line here.
Basically,
just above
this chin bone,
right around here.
This line marks the point
where the cheek line goes in.
It's the same for this too, it's bent like this.
This is how you get the shape of the face.
We need to draw the nose and lips here.
At this point, I want to say one thing.
I said not to draw the center line if possible.
Does that mean you shouldn't draw the center line at all?
No, I told you,
to draw it.
You can draw the center line.
But if you're going to draw it, please draw it in detail.
Starting from here,
the bridge of the nose goes in,
and it goes in the center of the eyes.
So the character can wear glasses.
And the nose sticks out,
and goes in,
and sticks out again.
The lips are pouting out,
the lower lips pout out,
and go in,
and the chin part sticks out a little bit.
Please draw all these lines.
If you're going to draw the center line,
erase it afterwards.
So you can make your drawing style.
When you check if the character's head is three-dimensional,
you can check it like that.
That's how it's expressed.
Add the sternocleidomastoid muscle on the neck.
In the back of the head,
put your neck together.
So far,
this would be a rough sketch
of one's face.
Now, I'm going to use this.
To approach a face at various angles.
It's a good idea to take a closer look at it.
First,
draw a cuboid.
Second,
align the facial features.
When you do this,
you know the step of aligning the center line.
It's good to take that step, too.
If you look at the eyes,
you can see the way we applied perspective
is applied in the same way.
Like this.
It's important that you
become familiar with the head's shape.
If you're finished up to here,
draw the contour lines.
It's what we did.
The facial contour lines.
Be aware of the parts that pop out
and pop in.
Control these areas and draw.
Now that you've done that,
apply your own deformers
to draw different angles
and different types
of your characters' faces.
For the hair,
I'll go into that in more detail in the next lecture.
So, today, I'll just go over it
briefly.
If we divide the hair into parts,
there's the front hair,
the side hair,
and the back hair.
The area we usually call
the sideburns,
let's say this is the side hair area.
So, let's say the ear is the starting point.
Then, at its front, there would be the front hair and the side hair.
Like this.
I'll draw the front and side hair.
And you can say that the hair behind the ear
is the back hair.
I think maintaining this big part,
would be a stable way to draw the hair.
Of course, you can part the hair.
Depending on the hairstyle of the character,
This part can change a little bit.
This area doesn't change,
I recommend you remember that.
Why do you need to remember this?
I'm going to tell you more information in the next class.
First, like this,
we went through the way how to draw the face accurately,
so far.
Let's learn how to draw beautifully.
What we learned earlier,
deformers for the eyes, nose, and lips,
belong to the essentials of how to draw well.
Later on, I hope you study
those parts together.
To draw a gorgeous face,
as expected, the proportions
will also play an important role.
Remember when we drew
a cute character and an old character?
We'll use these characters
to study how to draw.
Now, the first scenario.
Let's draw a childlike face.
If you want to draw a childlike face,
draw the eyebrows
slightly high up.
The nose should be
close to the eyes.
The face should be small,
while its head should be big.
That's the key point.
Then, we'd have a face that looks like this.
If you look at the basics,
it will look like this.
I'll make the eyebrows pop out.
Now that we've looked at a young face, let's draw a mature face.
With mature faces,
the eye size should be smaller.
I'll modify its gaze.
Just like I told you, the eyebrows
would be closer to the eyes.
Even with female characters,
it won't be too awkward when the eyebrows are close to the eyes.
So, when you're drawing a mature character,
don't be shy and just draw it carefully.
Some people keep heightening the eyebrows.
And, with the nose, describe the lower part as much as possible
and make sure it sticks to the mouth.
Lengthen the face
and shorten the head.
Then, the character would look like
it is more mature.
Now, let's create the atmosphere of the character.
So, what would be the atmosphere of the character?
It would be the character's first impression.
When I teach students, I frequently ask them
whether they are aiming for a cute look or a pretty look.
So, that means,
it is good to decide
whether you're drawing a cute character
or a pretty character.
And there are different ways of creating them depending on the tone.
Let's find out more about that.
Facial deformation is different according to the person.
I'm just going to tell you
how to apply deformation.
What I've told you
should be treated
just like parameters.
You can control
the amount of deformers depending on how much you want to apply them.
Now, when you're drawing a cute face,
let's look at the facial features first.
Eyes, nose, and mouth.
They make up most of the face.
Now, let's look at a mature character.
The eyes,
the nose and the mouth.
They shrunk quite a lot.
So, there's a lot of space in the face.
So, this is where there would be differences in creating the atmosphere.
What would that mean?
For us to perceive that a face is pretty,
we need a lot of information.
In general.
For example, if you have a lot of eyelashes,
it would look like a pretty face.
You need particular features to show
that you tried to make the face
look pretty.
So, that's how we'll perceive the character as being 'pretty'.
So, we can say that
a mature character's first impression
has a kind of disadvantage.
With the face on the left,
the facial features already cover most of it.
So, even with a few more descriptions, it will look pretty.
However, this face on the right
has small eyes, nose and mouth.
So, when we add only a few more features,
it won't look like we did much to it.
So, the solution is simple.
Depict things in more detail.
For instance, with eyelashes, you can draw more of them.
Some people draw eyelashes along the dimensions of the face
since eyelashes generally head upwards.
And they go more outwards.
Like this.
So, for the eye looking to the left,
some people make it stick out to the left like this.
Some people make it pop out to the right while it looks to the left.
There are people who express it like this.
I prefer the former way.
The bottom part that I did earlier,
the eyelashes...
Some people express the eyes in more detail.
To make the face look pretty.
Some people draw stars in the eyes.
Some people draw them in a shiny way.
In detail, too.
In the end,
to make the face look pretty,
people often do what I mentioned before.
To put more information
into their drawings.
People put in a lot of stuff
in as detailed a way as possible.
In the expression of the eyelashes as well.
What is this close to?
It's like wearing makeup.
In that part when people do the actual makeup,
Whether it's blush or anything...
they put on blush, too.
They put on eyebrows,
draw eyeliner and make it darker...
In the end, things like this
make the eyes look clearer.
So the key is to make this section look pretty.
So, if you wanted to make
this character look pretty,
the more you focus on the expression,
the better.
There's a lot of difference between before and after the expressions.
The lips as well.
Depending on the person who does it,
some just tint it.
So when you express this,
you may apply the deformers on the hair, too.
If you want to draw a cute character,
but don't want to make it look pretty...
so if you want it to be cute rather than pretty,
being pretty and cute are different.
Of course, some of you might aim for a cute and pretty look.
Then go for it.
If you want to make it look
cute and naive
but don't want to make it look pretty,
express it simply.
With the expressions,
instead of more detailed ones
like the one before, draw in
more simple details.
And, like that, the hair should be
round and big.
I'll go over this
more in detail in the next lecture,
so remember that.
Make the dimensions really big.
On the other hand, in this image
where you would draw a pretty character,
you will make the dimensions of the hair
small
and detailed.
See how the faces
on the left and right have a different atmosphere?
So...
We came up with a cute character and a pretty character.
It's the same with male characters.
A handsome character, and a cute character.
They all have the same theories behind them.
With male characters, you won't draw the eyelashes.
Although some of you may draw these parts.
So, remember now,
with male characters, do we use this kind of eyes often?
When you're drawing a male character,
they look more handsome when they have smaller eyes.
Like this.
Some people
draw in small dark circles
in this area here.
I'll split the hair into small pieces.
It's depicted like this.
So I can give a handsome impression.
So...
For both male characters and female characters,
you can adjust the age.
Let's sort it out.
The face is
a very important part of a painting.
For those who are going for a casual style,
you have to wrap yourself up and work hard.
It's a section that will continue to play an important role in the human body.
The first thing that's important when it comes to the face is
you have to draw it accurately.
Second,
draw it prettily.
I'm sure it's the same for the human body.
That's important.
To do that,
first,
to make it more accurate, the emphasized parts are
the head shape
and the facial features
including each part,
especially the eye socket for the eyes.
I'll emphasize that that is very important.
The total proportion of this head,
even the outer line of the face,
that was a way to draw it precisely.
To make the face look pretty,
the amount of expression,
I told you that you need to be able to control it.
When you want to give a cute impression
to a character,
don't depict it in detail as much.
Distribute things here and there.
Spread it out.
When you want to make it look pretty,
try to focus on the depiction much more.
So put it in a small section.
Using these two methods,
You can show your character in different ways.
Using those things,
try to draw a variety of faces.
As expected, you have to turn it around
and look at it from various angles.
From the previous class,
we were able to draw a simple human body.
And we were able to move that body.
We can attach it to a face now.
Although, having said this,
right after taking a class now,
I don't think you could draw it exactly like I have done.
As expected, for the drawing part, you'll need to continue to draw.
That's how you improve.
But for now, when it comes to how to improve,
I think I said enough.
I recommend you to keep on practicing those parts.
I think you can improve your skills from now on.
In the next class,
along with the hair that we didn't talk about in detail today,
I'm going to dress up the character.
We drew the human body of the character,
and moved and drew the hair.
If you can dress it up,
literally and theoretically,
you will be able to draw a character.
So, while drawing those parts,
for the demonstration part that I was lacking earlier,
I'll try to fill it in then.
See you in the next class.
That's a wrap for today.
Thank you for your efforts.