If you want to turn off the subtitles,
click [setting]-[tooltips]-['on' for PC, 'close' for mobile].
Hello.
Based on what we went through in the previous class,
we are going to change
the mood
of our character again.
Last time, we changed it to a cute vibe,
and a calm mood.
Today, I'm going to change this character
to be more aggressive,
and after that,
by applying various lighting conditions,
we'll take a look at
other examples.
Then first of all,
we're going to change it to a more aggressive image,
so we need to talk about what we need to do to achieve that.
Let's review what we went through
from when we expressed a cute character and a calm character
in the previous lecture.
The cute character.
Of course, we can't apply it to everything,
there are different ways of directing,
so it's good to know that before you move on.
Intensity.
Let's write down each characteristic.
So I said,
adjusting the contrast
is important
to make a strong image
but one which is not too bright
at a glance.
And the main elements, and sub elements.
The closer the distance is, the better it would be.
And various point elements,
I told you it's important to apply them,
although the concentration might be a bit distracting,
by applying them that much,
we need to make a full screen.
I said it's important before.
And overall, an image with warm coloring
would be more suitable in some ways.
And what else?
A cute situation,
in particular, the situation
has to be given, and it's really important.
That's what I said.
And the one with a calm image,
unlike this,
your eyes need to be comfortable,
so the gaze has to move
calmly,
and slowly,
the main element shouldn't take up too much space,
so not stretching out the main element too much,
but by reducing it a little bit,
to make sure to focus on the areas you need,
and for the rest of the sections, you can see them loosely.
That's how it goes.
Main element and sub elements,
and the distance,
contrary to the cute character,
I placed it far away.
By removing
the things that get in the way around it,
such as point elements,
compose an empty canvas.
Like the saying goes, "less is more".
I've made a calm image
by composing an empty canvas
and by using cool colors.
We used the surrounding elements,
among them, in the previous lecture,
we used water,
in highlighting.
Cute characters also have quite a lot of the highlights,
and since this one is also a point element,
we applied it a lot.
But this has highlights slightly added.
So those are the differences.
Then today,
let's work on building a strong character.
Usually, the overall contrast
of the strong character,
compared to the previous two ones,
it needs to be much stronger.
So that you can have a strong image at a glance.
The bright image that I mentioned earlier,
is used for this.
The overall color of the character is white.
Then it would be nice if the background color is a bit dark.
Like this.
It's okay to change it to completely black,
or give it a reddish color,
or a blue vibe.
Either way,
it's better to have some contrast,
between the background
and this character.
And here comes a difference between this one
and the cute character.
For the cute character,
by placing a lot of sub-elements in the main elements,
we spread the gaze a little bit.
Why did we do that?
If you get to concentrate too much,
it feels like a movie.
So if you concentrate too much,
it feels like its more serious,
and it makes us feel serious.
So the one like a kid,
has to be distractive.
To give a distractive vibe,
I spread the main elements.
Then, this strong image is actually,
if you compare it
in that way,
it has to have a strong impression,
which you can sense,
at a glance,
so I'm not going to put a lot of sub elements.
And for that,
we're going to give it a different light.
Let's use the one
that we used before.
Of course, we can use these lights as they are,
I'm going to change the lighting a little bit more.
When we studied about lighting,
we talked about Soft Light and Hard Light.
This one has a strong image
and with the image that bursts out at once,
I'm only going to show
a certain amount of the information in a character.
We decided not to add the surrounding elements.
Therefore, you need to be able to show a lot of things in a character.
If so,
rather than a simple Hard Light,
do Soft Light, which is applied more smoothly.
So there are many layers of light and shade.
The bright part and the dark part,
and the darker parts with the very dark parts,
they're divided into different layers.
I mentioned there's more information.
Therefore, the Soft Light is a bit more
effective in my point of view.
Let's use the strong light
heading to the face
of the character.
Instead, let's make sure,
the areas where light doesn't reach,
will be dark.
The creature in the back
also has to be dark.
So I will change the background
to make it close to black.
If it's blue and black,
I think it'll fit this image.
It's going to give a strong and cold image,
since the key color
of this character is bluish,
to show
the bluish color effectively,
I think it's good to draw it
a bit cold.
I'll choose the areas with mint color.
What I'm using right now
is the Magic Wand tool.
The basic shortcut is probably
the W key.
So if you press W,
you can use it a little faster.
I'm going to make the overall brightness a bit darker.
And I'm going to make it hard to see.
But, I mentioned before that I'm going for a strong impression.
Then how come I'm making these hard to see?
Because the area I want to show clearly is
the face area here.
When I first composed this illustration,
in other words, when I was drawing the thumbnail,
I wanted to make the face the main element.
That's what I said,
and I'm maintaining it.
So, to make the face the main element,
I'm only going to make this part strong.
Like this.
Similarly, I'm going to make the character's eyes
give a strong impression.
Here's a tip.
If you're going to add a lot of descriptions,
it might actually be good to put in less description
to the area you want to highlight.
If there's no description of one area,
while there's a lot of description in the other area,
the area without description
will look a bit intense.
That's why this kind of coloring
works pretty well.
But like I just said,
with this coloring,
there should be a lot of description in the other areas.
So, you need to describe the areas around it.
I'll make the center of the head bright
and make the center of the teeth bright.
I'll put everything in the middle,
and I'm going to put in less description for the other areas.
And,
if you can't see anything in the area with less description,
it will be a bit boring,
Then it would be nice to
see some detail for that area.
This circled area
is the part we're going to focus on.
It's good to arrange a little bit of
what you want to show around it.
So, what element
can play that role?
Let's think about that.
I'll make the tentacles in front of us
darker like this.
I'll draw it
as I show you
a bit of each part.
The light coming from the
back of this border
is called the Backlight.
The official name
of this light
would be Rim Light.
The light that comes into the border
of the character
makes the silhouette
quite clear.
It's one of the lightings
that's used a lot in game illustrations.
People use it to the extent that
they seem too dependent on Rim Light.
So it's important to learn
how to use Rim Light.
The important thing is
that it is a light coming from behind.
That's what's important.
It's all about coloring
where there is light,
so it's not about drawing outlines.
In the area where the hair is covered,
if you think that there would be no light,
it's better not to color this part.
Or you can add just a little bit of light.
Get rid of the areas
where there won't be light coming in.
It's something very important and simple.
But when most people
start to put in Rim Light,
many people draw it
like drawing a border.
You have to be careful not to do that.
Overall,
I'll keep
applying blue colors.
The Soft Light applied in the middle
and the color itself
will look bluish.
A cool color
can give off a cold feeling.
So, how are you going to show
the border areas
that you couldn't see?
I'm going to explain it now.
We're going to use the highlights.
It's similar to what we did before.
But I'm going to show the areas I want to show
little by little,
just like I did when I created a calm character.
I'm going to do this by
applying the highlights little by little everywhere.
Especially the belt.
This area where the belt is placed like this.
The most effective way to express that is
drawing the light coming from the top like this.
Do it like this.
Yes, that's it.
I'm not going to depict this in detail.
There are times when I don't express it
until it's actually done.
You might ask if you can do that,
because if you see as you work on it,
it might look unfinished.
But if you look at it from afar,
the belt area is very small,
and this area is the top area.
That's how it's depicted.
So, you don't have to depict anymore from here
since it already has three-dimensional details.
So, later on,
although we would depict this area
in more detail later,
this is how you would control the amount of description.
The subtraction itself,
where you exclude the detail
in the unnecessary sections,
is very important.
Especially for those who are drawing for the first time,
or for those who have the desire to draw cool illustrations,
and especially for those who
want to make something look cool,
I've seen a lot of cases where they can't control the amount of description.
The problem that usually happens
doesn't happen because there's no detail
or because they can't depict it well.
The most common problem happens because
there is too much description.
Because there is too much description,
and because you can't control the amount of description,
the amount of description keeps being divided.
There's too much description here and there.
The area that will be shown has been decided.
We decided to show the face.
I'm not going to show the bottom too much.
Then the part that won't be shown
won't need to be put into detail that much.
Because that area won't be shown.
The description
will be placed in the areas that you want to show the viewers.
Depict the areas in detail
that you want the viewers to see.
If the area
is not that important,
it's a good method to
just take out
the descriptive details.
I'm telling you this
because I hope
you can change your perception.
Description is not compulsory
in illustrations.
Gradations
or descriptions are actually sub elements.
It's almost done when the lighting starts...
Even if I just do this,
and if it looks complete from far away,
it will be a success.
But at that point, the description
would just be the sub element.
Rather than betting your life on the sub-elements,
and making the form distorted,
it's better to exclude some of the descriptions
and put them in areas that you want to highlight.
So, likewise, you can draw the best picture
you can with your current drawing skills.
In other words, if you're still not good at describing,
then you don't have to
forcefully increase the amount of description.
So, people usually ask me
how should they describe a character
and how they should touch it up.
I get a lot of questions like this.
But, touching up a drawing
has similarities with the actual drawing process.
So, your skills won't increase
right at once.
We'll see this later on and
I'll explain it further then.
But I normally call it brush power.
If you want to master
brush power,
you can say that it takes around a few years.
It's something you need to learn naturally as you draw,
so, for now, just learn that
you will come to acquire the necessary skills later on.
Don't focus too much on things like
gradation and description.
When you want to express a drawing,
especially a specialized drawing,
when you just use the lighting well,
you can make your drawing look complete.
In fact, right now,
I didn't put in too much description.
I only gave light to the top.
But wouldn't it be hard to
call it a proper description?
That's all I described.
That's it.
There's nothing special.
You can even count
the creases on the clothes.
I think maybe I drew around five.
So, even if I drew around that much,
the overall form of the illustration will be settled.
I don't even need more creases for this area.
It's not where you want to show it, right?
If you can just clearly show
this top area, which is the area we want to show,
you don't need to describe the rest of the illustration.
Remember that
they're the additional elements.
Please don't forget that.
I was talking about contrast before.
I think I told you that
when there's the Cast Shadow and the Form Shadow,
the Cast Shadow is the shadow between objects.
The Form Shadow forms because of
the object's three-dimensional form.
That's what I said.
I also explained
that because Form Shadow has less contrast
than a Cast Shadow,
people usually work on Cast Shadow first.
That's what I said.
With creases on clothes,
they are actually
a mixture of Cast Shadow and Form Shadow.
For example,
there are creases on the shirt,
like this one on the shirt.
For deep creases on clothes, when the light comes in,
there will be shadows.
This won't create a shadow like that.
So in this case, Form Shadow,
if it sticks out like this,
Cast Shadow is applied.
Of course, that works like that.
But let's take a look at this.
This one doesn't protrude up
that much.
The amount of light on this side and that side,
has no dramatic difference.
Unless...
So in a case like this,
it's important to express the creases,
applying low contrast,
to make it so that there's not much difference.
Just like this,
adjust it gently.
If there's low contrast,
when you look at it in black and white,
the difference between bright and dark parts
has to be tiny.
When you look at it like this,
it'd be good if the difference
between the bright and dark parts come out less.
It looks like this.
But the background gets dark,
and just by making the middle part stand out,
the illustration already gets
more intense to some extent.
Of course, I won't finish it here.
I said that
I'd put some highlights on the outer edge
to show you a few of the gazes,
but that doesn't seem to be honest.
So far,
what else can I use at this point?
At this point as well.
Let's think about it.
An element that gives you a strong impression.
It shouldn't be too cute.
Then,
what elements can I use?
I think there might be a liquid.
Because the character uses tentacles,
we can make
liquid flow around its tentacle.
We can make the liquid sticky
over here.
Or, I can just
draw an eye over here
in the mouth.
Then, it would look scary overall.
These elements would look good.
I can put in these elements around it too.
Scary, right?
Let's work on it by increasing
these kinds of things.
On the bottom of the background,
draw something like this,
to make it look like blood,
so that we could express
the violence
of the character.
Let's put them in place like this.
So that the middle part of the eye can be a point,
use the eye makeup that we used
when we were working on the calm character.
You can see that
the overall makeup we used
is similar to a calm character.
But, even so,
you should use the methods you used for creating a cute character too.
That way, we can make it have a strong impact.
For a strong impact,
make sure the viewers focus on a certain area.
Oh, this is where the viewers would focus.
You should decide things like that.
Other than that area, the viewers shouldn't be focusing on the other areas.
But, there should be a strong contrast.
It should overall be bright.
That way, the main element
will give a strong impression.
So, if you look at the difference,
when you show a cute character,
overall, it has an exciting feeling.
You should make it look exciting.
This is the main area.
These areas are additional areas.
So, when you express them,
you should highlight the main area,
but you also have to highlight the additional areas.
Let's say 0 is around here.
Then, if you're drawing a calm character,
you won't describe the parts that you won't highlight.
Of course, you need to highlight some areas.
But, these areas won't be that strong.
That way, it will be overall calm.
The main area.
With a character with a strong impression,
you won't highlight
the areas that you shouldn't highlight.
I'll dramatically highlight the parts I want to highlight.
Other areas won't be highlighted.
Main area.
There's this difference.
So, if you decide
how much you'll highlight certain areas,
your final result will be closer
to the image you want.
I'm going to add some liquid to the hat.
I'll make the overall gaze
flow downwards.
But, I'm going to maintain the character's calm gaze.
I want to give it a cold feeling.
If I wanted to make this illustration feel powerful,
I would have used a gaze that flows from bottom to top.
But if I use that kind of gaze flow,
I won't be able to
create a mood
where the character looks extremely calm.
So, I'll just use the gaze
that goes downwards.
The shape itself
looks like a triangle.
So, this object will make
the gaze go down.
Depending on your directing skills,
you can put these in, too.
It's okay to add them in bit by bit.
So, I can put it in like this.
But, if this becomes too much,
the overall mood could change.
Let's add just a little bit.
It'd be nice to have some fog.
I'll spray it.
I'll use the Eraser tool, too.
I'm going to use a fun method here.
I don't want to just use it like this.
So,
see this paint can on the left?
If you look at the bottom, there is the Smudge Tool.
But,
you can use it as another function.
Some people see it as a Blur Tool.
Please change this to the Smudge Tool.
This Smudge Tool pushes things out.
It's like pushing something with our hands.
The downside is that it uses up
too much of your computer's memory.
So, if your computer has low memory,
be careful when you use it.
If you make a mistake, the file could be erased.
So, it's good to save periodically as you're working.
So I drew some fog around it.
That Smudge Tool is the best tool to edit this form.
It's hard to draw while erasing everything.
It's a bit uncomfortable.
Like this, I'll create a fog
that lurks at the bottom.
It brings out the dreary atmosphere.
And for the gaze,
I'll make it
go to the bottom.
Make the gaze go right and left.
For the overall composition,
I'm going to use a triangular composition
that we learned before.
Using the overall triangular silhouette,
I'll arrange it
so that the gaze goes downwards
to create a calm image.
Let's use what we used before.
We used this briefly for creating cute characters.
Remember when we used the Fade Out effect?
As I said before, with this illustration,
the viewers need to focus on the middle part.
As such, unnecessary sections
should be removed.
I'm going to use the Multiply Layer.
Let's create areas
that can't be seen.
When I was creating a cute character,
I applied this lightly.
But, you don't have to apply this lightly now.
When it's bright,
it's actually better.
To make the background look more intense,
I'll apply lots of key colors,
and I'll continue.
Because I'm coloring the areas around the character's face,
it will be okay to apply it
when it's applied just a bit.
But if you apply it too much, viewers can't focus on the face.
The point is to control the amount of color.
Use it to make the drawing look more intense.
This character's mouth is currently blue.
It has a very unique design with a tongue.
So, I'm going to utilize this
and hang these objects.
It looks as if it's drooling.
The impression
will be very intense.
Before and after.
Of course, if I want to give it a serious look,
it's okay to leave these out.
Instead, you can add bloodstains.
If you do it like this,
the character will give off
a very strong impression.
I'll display it
with the other illustrations I did before.
These are the three illustrations that we did.
The basics.
Cute, calm, and strong.
You'll be able to see something different
from the overall impressions.
Like this, you can create various moods
with illustrations.
Even if it's based on the same sketch,
there's a difference in the mood.
So, it's important to use these
to create the image
and compose it
and express what you've composed.
You should keep practicing like that.
It's very important.
Now that we've done it up to here,
I'm going to create another mood
for this character.
I'm going to use another method this time.
Earlier, we created atmospheres
according to the mood we wanted to create.
This time, let's give a reason
that's a bit different from that.
This time, I'm going to create canvases
that become different depending on
the color you want to use,
the lighting you intend to give,
or the background you intend to use.
Background color.
While learning about lighting,
we studied background color.
Now, let's use it
in the actual drawing process.
What kind of backgrounds
are commonly used?
There could be an outdoor background.
Especially, we could use different times of the day
such as morning, afternoon, evening,
night, and dusk.
You can use these times roughly.
Then, let's see how we can show them
based on the lighting.
Let's edit as we go on.
First of all,
let's say you want to organize
a daytime background.
Let's think about the characteristics of daylight.
I'm going to draw the backgrounds.
I'm not going to draw it in detail.
For people who think
it's so hard to draw the background,
then, it'd be good to Photoshop your illustration with a reference.
When you use photos,
it'd be nice if you do the filtering as well.
If you click,
[Filter] - [Filter Gallery],
if you click in here,
a Photoshop window pops up,
things like this come up,
and there are many effects.
Try to control anything,
find the effect that you want,
and apply it.
By using that to edit the photos,
you can make it as the background of your illustration.
First of all,
I'll draw one and use it.
Let's set it up to be outside
on a sunny day.
There are clouds,
and although it doesn't fit the character,
you can imagine that this character went out on a picnic.
I'll make the floor look like asphalt.
Something like this.
It becomes a bright background.
Let's think about the conditions of daylight.
What color is the sunlight?
Actually, the sunlight
is called white light.
It includes all kinds of colors.
But among them,
it's a bit on the yellowish side.
If you look at pictures of the sun in space,
it's burning yellow.
So much so that,
to a certain extent,
the yellow light is a bit strong.
So, the sections which are exposed to the sunlight
tend to have
a bit of a reddish color.
So, under the premise that this character
is the area that receives light,
overall, a yellow color
is added to the canvas.
The shadow area,
well, it's different case by case,
but basically,
it will have a bluish color.
Why does that happen?
With shadowy areas,
less light comes in
compared the lighted areas.
What does that mean?
When there is an object,
there is the lighted area
and the areas without light.
The background color is blue
and the light color is yellow.
This area here, where it receives strong light,
will have a strong yellowish color.
With the background color,
there is the main light,
and the light that's reflected around it
comes in.
So, it's basically reflected light.
It's been reflected once.
It already
got rid of light from someplace else,
so it's naturally weaker
than the strong light coming from the main source.
So, this area, where it is affected a lot by light,
will have the same color
as the light itself.
Understand it like that.
But, there are areas that aren't affected by light.
The shadows.
Because this shadow
isn't affected by the light a lot,
if we put it the other way around,
the light doesn't reach the shadow.
So, it will be more affected by
the background color.
If we made this area yellowish,
this light and shadow area
will be more bluish
since that was the background color.
Think of it that way.
Then, why does the outdoor background
have a blue background color?
Well, it's simple.
The sky is blue.
In the air, there are
a lot of blue light particles.
So, blue color is reflected.
Think of it like that.
So, the shadows in the character,
in other words, these shadows
that we worked on before,
become blue.
Then, we are now going to apply
the tertiary colors of light and shadow.
When you're applying tertiary colors,
just follow the color of the light.
What color was the light?
It was a yellowish, reddish color.
I'm going to use
a Normal Layer.
Like this.
So, we now have
a reddish tertiary color.
So, I described the tertiary color
by using the outer light.
But, if they're in the same amounts,
it won't look pretty.
If you've applied that,
and if you don't like,
you will want to edit it.
Then, what can you do?
I'll copy
the same layer in.
Copy the same layer in,
and apply the same effects.
If you see
the top right here,
there's the Opacity slider.
Slide the Opacity
to 0%.
What happens
when you slide it?
The color we colored in disappears,
and only the outer light will stay.
Like this.
What we're going to do now is
right-click on the layer.
If you see here,
you'll see the menu option [Rasterize Layer].
What is this?
This combines
this outer light and the layer underneath it
into one.
The opacity is set to 0%.
If I rasterize it,
the Layer underneath it disappears
and only the outer light
that we colored on
the outlines will stay.
As an example, I will use the Selection Tool
to select an area like this.
Then, only this outer area
will be selected like this.
Then remember how,
I applied a Multiply Layer?
I'll make it into a Multiply Layer.
If I turn the above Layer on,
then the shadows
and the outer lights will be separated.
And, within the outer light that's been separated,
I will erase the areas I don't like.
Now, over here,
I'll add a new Layer.
This time, I'm going to apply
the Overlay effect.
I said I was going to give it a yellow color, right?
In the areas that receive light,
I'm going to make sure
that a bright yellow light comes in.
On the other hand, the areas that don't receive light
will receive some blue light.
Especially, we learned that for the background objects
an air perspective is applied,
in the previous lecture.
When we apply that,
we add a lot of the air color.
So, in this case, we would add in a lot of blue.
Make sure to apply bluish colors
to the hair.
It's a good area, right?
Like this.
Because it gets sunlight,
it would be natural that
the amount of shadow decreases.
If I do this,
it will be an illustration
that receives strong sunlight.
Now, I'll add other lights too.
This is example number 1.
Now, I'm going to make
an evening background
with a sunset.
When we add sunset,
the blue background color that we looked at before,
will be spread out like this.
When there's sunset, the sky is usually orange.
With the evening sky,
the sky itself will be an orange color.
So, the background color that is applied to the character
will be changed to a red color.
The light that's coming in is a yellowish color,
and the background color is red.
So, the color would overall be uniform.
Let's change the sky color first.
The tentacle in the back
disturbs our eyesight, so I'll exclude it.
So, the overall illustration
will be a piece
with a strong orange color.
Also, the character
will be an overall orangeish color
compared to its original color.
So, the original color will be changed a lot.
We learned this previously with lighting, remember?
When a blue object receives yellow light,
there's no color that it can reflect.
With the Color Range tool,
I'll make these areas
very low saturated -
in fact, they'll be a grayish color.
So, this will be my workflow.
Now, I'll apply the shadows.
I want to utilize what I've used before,
but the light direction has changed.
So, I'll apply that change.
I'll make it a bit dark.
This one had a bluish color.
So, it doesn't fit this illustration.
I'll make it a bit more reddish.
Now, with this lighted area,
I'll add a new Layer.
I'm going to add a Screen Layer.
This time, the light won't be completely white,
but instead, it will be a yellowish light.
The direction of the light will be
coming from the top left.
I'll adjust the opacity
to make sure I have the brightness I want.
The light that comes right in front of the character
is a very weak light.
So, it will be kind of like a Soft Light.
I'll give more light to the character's face
like this.
I'll adjust it so that
the facial area will be emphasized.
Let's make it a bit more of an orange color.
If there's light coming in from the top left,
I told you that
you need to observe carefully
how the light will come in
and which areas will receive light.
So, when doing that,
it's important to observe the object as its basic form.
You shouldn't perceive it as
a cloth, a skin, or an eye.
Is it headed towards the top left?
Or, is it headed towards the top right?
These aspects
are more important.
Because it is all about lighting,
describing the texture
will come in later.
We're not describing the texture now.
Just simply think of
whether a certain area
receives light or not.
Think of these things.
Because of the arm on the left,
a Cast Shadow would be formed.
There could also be areas
covered with hair.
You have to consider these things.
An eyeball also has three-dimensional characteristics.
When it receives the light,
it could shine.
But, the description of the three-dimensional aspects
will have less deformers applied to it.
Because there are less deformers,
it will look less casual.
So, you can apply it depending on the situation.
If it looks pretty after you've applied it, use it.
If it doesn't, don't use it.
That's all.
It's good to add tertiary colors as well.
I'll use the outer light
to add in the tertiary colors.
It will be good if these colors
are overall reddish.
If the inside of the hair
and if the inside of the clothes
are just cotton,
it will have this color.
But, there will be some modifications.
The character's clothing
and the mint color on the hair
is made up of material
that shines.
So, in that case,
it's okay to
apply the colors
of these materials.
But, if you apply them too much,
the impact of the light will be too weak.
So, add in just a little bit.
Make sure of that.
Just little by little.
Just make sure the light impact isn't weak.
If you want to describe the background as well,
and if it is a moody background,
you can put in these.
Things like barbed wire.
We can add a warning sign
to the pillars.
Draw it
so that it matches
the character's perspective.
In character illustration,
the background is the sub element.
So, don't focus too much on it.
But, if you want to show the background,
then,
you should focus on it.
With illustrations,
the subject changes depending on
what you want to show.
An illustrator
is someone
who depicts things.
So,
I'll add in some highlights.
I won't make it too sparkly.
Because with sunsets,
the light is subtle.
So, now that we're done,
we need to do some editing.
I'll create a new Layer.
I'll use the Overlay function
this time as well.
I use Overlay often.
I'm going to make the light spread out,
on the top left.
I call this
scattering light.
Actually, light
isn't something
that comes only in places that it should,
in a logical way.
It will be reflected all around.
Since the light source
is the Sun,
it's too big to say that it's a dot.
So, light spreads around the places it reaches.
So, around the areas that are lighted,
add Overlay like this,
and make it bright.
Then, it will look like
a more natural, pretty light.
The overall illustration will be fancier as well.
So, make sure to
apply the scattering light.
So,
I also described an illustration
with the sunset light.
Let's draw
another illustration, too.
The sunlight that we drew before.
I'll give it some highlights here.
The eyes look too scary.
And the sunset.
We saw the differences
between the two situations.
This time, the background will be set
at night.
We applied daylight
and sunset,
so, now, it will be a night sky.
I'll use the Curve Tool
to make it
dark.
Make the character
dark,
just like this.
I'll add the blue light, too.
The mint color of the character
could become slightly stronger
than the previous color.
This is because the blue object
received blue light.
So, for this object,
there's more reflected light.
So, a stronger light
will be applied.
But, it will be blue.
Mint is closer to a green color,
and green
is a mixture of yellow and blue.
Overall, if I edited it
like this...
Let's edit
the tentacles, too.
Now, I'll add
more light to it.
The gray part doesn't have
a strong blueish color.
Select this area as well.
Using the Color Range Tool,
select, and then,
I'll apply a bit more blue.
I want it to feel bright.
Here,
I'll make a Layer.
Since there's darkness overall,
now we can give it some light.
Using the Screen Layer,
I'm going to apply some Backlight.
I also told you
we call this Meme Light.
It's important to work while
you think about the areas where the light comes in
and the areas that don't.
Character and background.
The character is dark now,
and the background is dark, too.
As such, the character and the background
should be separated.
You can give it
some gradation.
When we were analyzing references,
we did this part before.
Do you remember?
In this case, the area where the light from the back touches
will be the areas
that I'm painting as the Back Light.
That means
all the parts that I'm not applying Back Light to
are in shadow.
What's a shadow?
It's a part where there's no light.
Since this area doesn't get any light,
you might ask, shouldn't it be just black?
I explained this part before.
In this area,
the light is reflected from the surroundings
and the background light is coming from all directions.
So, that's why
we can see this character.
If it weren't for that light,
this character would be black,
and only the Back Light could be seen.
To show you an example,
with only the silhouette,
it will be like this.
As expected, with this process
you can turn off the Pen Pressure.
If you're only thinking about the area,
do it like this.
As expected... the tertiary colors.
This time, it's not just the orangeish colors.
It's getting blue light,
which is the moonlight coming from behind.
So, the tertiary color will also look a bit blue.
Let's put it in like this.
But if I do this,
the drawing will be too bland.
Some areas can't be seen clearly.
It's kind of boring.
From here,
you need some direction skills.
When we draw characters with a night background,
you need to think that the light coming from the front
has some intensity.
When I was working on the sunset background,
I used the light in the middle as Soft Light,
and I applied some light to the lower part of the face.
Similarly,
with the night background,
I made the bottom look brighter,
to get some light.
You can increase
the density of the light
to increase
the visible areas.
People see the bright areas first.
To put it the other way around,
it's hard to draw attention
with dark spaces.
If this illustration goes wrong,
it could be an illustration that doesn't have anything to see in it.
So, to avoid doing that,
so that the viewers can definitely feel they are seeing something,
I'll add a lot of highlights.
I'm going to make the eyes have a strong impression.
I'll show it to you like this.
Nocturnal animals
have shining eyes at night.
They actually look really cool.
You might think they look scary.
There are a lot of elements like that.
So, I'll make these elements
like they're glow-in-the-dark.
I'll add a lot of highlights.
To make the drawing look shiny,
when we put highlights on the hair,
people often mistake something.
Let's talk about this first.
When you want to give it Back Light,
and when you highlight it,
some people apply it like this.
You might ask yourself,
what's wrong with that?
The character is not receiving
the light from the left.
The reason why this character got brighter is
because it received
the light from the side and the back light.
So, that's it for now.
So, this area is the shadow.
The light that this area receives
is not this light.
It's not the light that came from the side.
The light that this part receives
only comes from the front.
So, as the highlight goes to the left,
there's no need to get bigger.
When you color it
and when you add the density later,
the more you go to the left,
there's no need to be bright.
There are many people who misunderstand this.
The light that's received here
only receives the light from the front.
Only the background light is received.
So, only the areas that are close to our eyes will get brighter.
So don't get it wrong.
People often make mistakes here.
The tool I'm using right now is
the Dodge Tool.
The default shortcut is the O button.
The tool that uses this button,
which is the Dodge Tool,
brightens up the picture.
If you use it too much, the picture will look like it's burning.
So, please don't use it too much.
Like this,
I'll make the middle area
brighter more effectively.
I'll apply some more blue.
Do it like this.
Since it's nighttime, I said I'm going to add some sparkles.
That's what I wanted to do.
I put some sparkles around the character.
Like this, you can now create
illustrations with a night sky.
Let's look at the difference from the previous one,
and let's see if it looks like night.
So, let's list the differences.
With this illustration,
I made various variations.
There's a clear difference in the atmosphere.
If you look at the illustration examples I gave today,
you can see
that the time has changed.
So when you make an illustration like this,
you need to tailor it to the nuances
you want to create.
So if there's a light you want to use,
with the light direction,
you can create illustrations according to that.
If you look at this,
you can see that the mood changed gradually.
First,
with the bright light, we gave it a cute and warm image.
For the second one,
it was a pretty and bright image.
The third one was
a strong image.
Depending on the light you want to use,
the mood changes.
So it's important to change the illustration
depending on the lighting you want to give it.
Like this,
with one illustration,
we drew them in different types.
What I want to say to you
once more is,
just because I emphasized light,
don't be too obsessed with it.
What am I trying to say?
Drawing is something that can be done freely.
Especially with casual drawings,
you can draw
much more freely.
Because of that, you can direct it like...
for example,
by changing the background to purple.
Make the areas
such as the light and dark parts
of the character
like this.
Overall, it's important that the parts that receive light
become brighter.
If it becomes bright in black and white, there's no problem.
So if it gets brighter when you see it in black and white,
even if the saturation gets strong,
it's not that important,
no matter how the hues change.
In painting,
if you think about the picture itself,
it's not that important.
When you brightened the middle area like this,
or change the color like this,
as long as they suit each other,
it won't be a problem.
The way to use this Lasso Tool is,
you don't even have to use a drawing tablet.
Sometimes, I just work with a mouse.
Most of the time, of course, I use a drawing tablet.
Even if you go in like this, you'll see that
it still becomes an okay illustration.
In other words, in the illustration,
the coloring
is something really free.
Because of that, you can make many variations
by yourself like this.
Even if I draw only one piece of illustration,
make various examples.
I'd like to emphasize that
if you increase the number
of the type of illustrations you can draw,
it would be good.
That's one of the things I'd like to emphasize.
While talking about coloring,
there's one last thing I want to say.
You can control the contrast.
I'll tell you in the description part,
but later on,
you can use
many editing methods.
This can also be a way
of drawing an illustration.
I'll put it on display.
So like this,
we learned how to make a full illustration.
Next time, I'll pick one of these
that I like the most,
and I'll tell you
how to finish it,
up to the completion stage.
You will then learn how to
change the expression depending on the mood.
It will be good
if you can choose how to color your illustration
according to
what kind of illustration
you're going for.
Let's wrap up today's class.
I'll see you again
in the next lecture.
Keep up the great work.